1. n-1

2. 

a) The p_lnk variable is a pointer to another OS_TCB variable. The purpose of the p_lnk variable is to allow OS_TCB instances to be linked as a linked list (possibly keeping track of tasks that are in queue to be executed or pushed onto the stack)
b) The stack variable points to a block of memory in the stack memory pool that has been allocated to the pertaining OS_TCB instance. The pointer, stack, points to the lowest memory address of the task stack. The tsk_stack variable contains the memory address of the top of the task stack.
c) Doing this cast will not preserve the value of the p_lnk field. Casting a pointer simply reinterprets the bits at the memory address that the pointer is pointing too. The structure OS_XCB has the p_lnk field starting at a one byte offset because there is a U8 field before it. The structure OS_TCB has the p_lnk field starting at a five byte offset, because it has four U8 field variables before it. Therefore accessing p_lnk after the cast is looking at a different memory location.

3. mp_tcb is an array with size equal to the size of a TCB times the maximum number of TCBs. It is used as a reference for TCB allocation (memory pool). Similarly, mp_stk is a memory pool used as reference for system stack allocation. Its size is equal to the size of a task stack, multiplied by the maximum number of tasks.

R1 to R12 , LR and initial PC are pushed onto the stack...
The lower 16 bits of the os_stackinfo global variable contain the default task stack size. (rtx_lib.c line 46)
When within the init_stack function, the first item pushed onto the task stack may be accessed by stk[13], elsewhere, it can be accessed by adding 13*4 (each item is 1 word, 4 bytes, first item pushed is 13 items before the top of stack) to the address stored in tsk_stack field (with OS_TCB).
Iterate through os_active_TCB, and check the state for !RUNNING. Check the value of the field tsk_stack, for the memory address. The address points to the top of the task stack (the last added item).
Same thing for RUNNING.




